Father ordered me
Отец приказал мне
To investigate the details of your treason
выяснить детали твоего мятежа
If you confess voluntarily
Если сам признаешься
You can avoid physical punishment
избежишь пыток
I led troops
Я повёл войска
To
чтобы
Investigate the embezzlement of relief funds
расследовать хищение средств помощи
You say I committed treason
Ты говоришь что я поднял мятеж
What evidence do you have?
где доказательства
Evidence
Доказательства
That warehouse full of armor and weapons
это целый склад доспехов и оружия
Great Xuan's law
По законам Великой Сюань
Privately storing ten sets of armor
тайное хранение десяти комплектов доспехов
Is considered treason
приравнивается к мятежу
What you stored
А у тебя их
Far exceeds ten sets
куда больше десяти
That is crime one
Это первое преступление
Without orders
Без указа
Privately deploying city defense troops
самовольно вывел городскую стражу
Causing the capital's defenses to be empty
оставив столицу беззащитной
Endangering the Son of Heaven
подвергнув императора опасности
That is crime two
Это второе преступление
Not to mention
И даже не вникая
Whether you actually had treasonous thoughts
были ли у тебя мысли о мятеже
Just these two crimes alone
по этим двум пунктам
Either one
любой из них
You cannot escape death
и тебе не избежать смерти